<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Projects | Susim Mukul Roy</title><link>https://SusimRoy.github.io/tag/research-projects/</link><atom:link href="https://SusimRoy.github.io/tag/research-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Research Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://SusimRoy.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Research Projects</title><link>https://SusimRoy.github.io/tag/research-projects/</link></image><item><title>Attacking DDPMs through Class Activation Maps</title><link>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project18/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project18/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Conducted an extensive literature survey of diffusion models and their advantages and disadvantages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implemented an architecture which works with different pretrained DDPMs and classifiers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developed a novel adversarial attack using the Class-Activation Maps of classifiers and the predicted noise maps from the UNet model of a DDPM.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Worked with datasets like CIFAR10, CelebaHQ&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Intensity Optimized CT Reconstruction</title><link>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Modelling of noise for CT simulations(e.g. Poisson-noise)by considering spatially non-uniform intensity distributions and in limited dosage environments(ULDCT).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a pattern so that the intensity distribution becomes learnable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Apply an appropriate reconstruction technique which takes care of artifacts or likely noise patterns and generates back the original image which has high metric values when compared with ssim etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>On Discriminating Intentional Adversarial Perturbations with Unintentional Noises</title><link>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project19/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project19/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We propose a class-independent detection method, CIAI, using Maximum Mean Discrepancy and classifying the intended and unintended noise separately.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We show how both types of noises affect the classification accuracy for gender prediction on the CelebA dataset. We show the detection accuracy which is comparable and at times exceeds the previous state-of-the-art detection methods including performance on unseen attacks.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Using attention maps we further show features that help with the prediction of gender and detection of noises.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Visual Motion Analysis from Images and Videos</title><link>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project16/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project16/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The main objective was to work towards developing a software to find the optimal time to spray fungicides to prevent the spread of FHB disease among the common vegetation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wheat and Canola flower data collection and annotation using SCVAT and storing them as PASCAL-VOC or YOLO format.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improving Yolov8 and Efficient-Det(pytorch version) algorithms to work on the created dataset by tuning hyperparameters in the former case and incorporating an attention module(e.g. CBAM) in the latter case.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deployment of the trained models on the &lt;a href="https://demo.sga.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">demo Website&lt;/a> for usage by farmers and similar people for FHB prevention.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Detecting Adversarial Perturbations While Determining Intentional and Unintentional Noises</title><link>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We proposed a class-independent detection method, CIAI, using Maximum Mean Discrepancy which classifies the intended(adversarial attacks) and unintended(for e.g. Gaussian) noise separately.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The algorithm is multistage indicating that in the first stage, we use an MMD-based loss to train a Vision
Transformer initialized with trained classifier weights and in the second stage we use the trained detector for classification by freezing all the layers and adding three trainable layers for training.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We show the detection accuracy which is comparable and at times exceeds the previous state-of-the-art detection methods, including performance on unseen attacks.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Referring Moving Object Segmentation</title><link>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://SusimRoy.github.io/project/project4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Conducted an extensive literature survey to understand the working of the SOTA models like Referformer, MTTR etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improved RefVos by including the temporal information from the frames by taking their difference and sending it as input along with the 2nd frame among every 3 consecutive frame.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To capture the new variety of features, made a new convolutional decoder to interpret the spatial and temporal information into accurately segmenting the object.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Researched into joining the language and visual features using modules introduced by different papers such as a Multi-Scale Cross-Modal Feature Mining technique among others.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extended the training and testing dataset to JHMDB and DAVIS-17 along with the standard A2D dataset.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>